

PRACHI PANDYA

SALES PROFESSIONAL ♥ INDIA 09725147950

• DETAILS •

India 09725147950 prachipandya06@gmail.com

Date of birth 06.12.1996

LINKS

<u>LinkedIn</u>

SKILLS

Computer Skills

Ability to Multitask

Leadership Skills

Decision Making

Problem Solving

Adaptability

Ability to Work Under Pressure

Communication Skills

Teamwork

Direct Sales

Communication and Negotiation

Objection Handling

Customer Service

Empathy

LANGUAGES

Hindi

English

Gujarati

Punjabi

PROFILE

Efficient and effective sales representative with over 6 years of experience in hotel sales and managing business, professional, and corporate client accounts. Exceeded sales goals by more than 15%. Developing business by both proactive and reactive means. Seeking to leverage solid negotiation skills and extensive product knowledge to be at the managerial position.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Sales manager at Hyatt Regency, Amritsar

January 2023 — Present

Analysing the local client potential

Increasing revenue generation by 5%

Increasing business repo with new clients

Managing different market segments

Assistant Sales Manager at Hyatt Regency Amritsar, Amritsar

August 2021 — Present

Working upon new market with new strategies

Strategizing the market segments with new perception

Comprehensive sales training to associates

Strategizing and budgeting

Event handling

Sales Executive at Courtyard by Marriott Sindhu Bhawan Road (Pre-Opening), Ahmedabad

October 2020 — May 2021

- Maintaining corporate data base.
- Responsible for corporate and Travel agent room sales for the hotel.
- Executes and supports the operational aspects of business booked.
- Managing and Develops relationships with key internal and external stakeholders.
- Acquiring and developing new business accounts and preparing sales accountability.

Events Executive at Hyatt regency, Chennai

February 2020 — June 2020

- Re-actively supporting department by closing the events.
- Major portfolio managed for associations like JITO, Rotary and gujarati,
- Handled corporate events.

HOBBIES

Motorcycling Writing snippets Podcasting

C&E Executive at DoubleTree by Hilton (Pre-Opening), Ahmedabad

November 2018 — January 2020

- Assisting in building business strategies.
- Regular sales blitzing and physical calling for acquiring business.
- Major portfolio handled; associations, pharma companies, lifestyle, automobiles, exhibitions, weddings, groups and MICE.
- · Achieveing budgets quarterly by 20%.
- · Managing PR with B2B event planners and wedding planners,
- Closing groups, handling operational aspects; both reactively and proactively.
- Understanding hotel and showing around to the guests.
- Preparing detailed proposals, contracts and Banquet event orders.
- Detailing of the event with the event planner and event coordinator.

Sales Coordinator at Hyatt, Ahmedabad

June 2017 — October 2018

- Organizing administrative work.
- · Reactively closing events.
- Managing rooms, events and MICE queries through walk-in guests.
- Preparing proposals, contracts and Banquet event orders efficiently.
- · Preparing daily reports.

Tele Sales Executive at TLC, Courtyard by Marriott, Ahmedabad

August 2016 — January 2017

- Selling membership for Club Marriott, loyalty programme for the hotel.
- · Achieveing weekly and monthly budgets.

Market Analyst at Insight Board Research, Ahmedabad

August 2015 — September 2016

- Data mapping and secondary sales.
- Collecting data, reviews and survey through Computer Assisted Telephonic interviews globally.
- Worked for clients like AT&T, Oracle, Apple and Windows

EDUCATION

Higher Secondary, The New Tulip International School, Ahmedabad April 2012 — March 2014

Bachelors of Arts in Psychology, Gujarat University, Ahmedabad June 2014 — April 2017

■ REFERENCES

• References available upon request

Software used

Working knowledge for softwares-

- Opera
- Envision
- SFA Web
- Reserve
- Delphi FDC
- OnQ PMS